Manuel A. Quintero Coronel

manuelquinteroc.github.io

ightharpoonup maq25@cam.ac.uk • • manuelquinteroc • in manuelquinteroc • (+52) 1 56 11640566

Personal

I am a highly self-motivated student with a strong background in mathematics and statistics, with over three years working as a research assistant mainly with time series and causal inference using several statistical software. I am also interested in teaching: I have taught three courses at the graduate and undergraduate levels.

FIELDS OF INTEREST

- Mathematical Statistics High-Dimensional Data Analysis, Causal Inference, and Machine Learning.
- Pure Mathematics Functional Analysis, Partial Differential Equations, and Real Analysis.
- Mathematical Economics Game Theory, DSGE models, and Microeconometrics.

EDUCATION

Cambridge University, Cambridge, UK 2022 - 2023 MASt in Mathematical Statistics (Part iii). Areas of study: Advanced Probability, Modern Statistical Methods, Topics in Statistical Theory, Causal Inference, Functional Data Analysis, Statistical Learning in Practice, Concentration Inequalities, and Functional Analysis. Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico, CDMX, Mexico 2015 - 2020 Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics (Honours). GPA: 9.49 / 10.0 (Top 2.64%) Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico, CDMX, Mexico 2015 - 2020 Bachelor of Arts in Economics (Honours). GPA: 9.28 / 10.0 (Top 4.49%) Instituto Chapultepec, Culiacan, Mexico 2015 High School Diploma - Valedictorian Bodwell High School, Vancouver, Canada 2014 High School Diploma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant (Harvard, MIT, ITAM)

Mar 2021-Present

Supervisor: Horacio Larreguy (Harvard-ITAM), and Fotini Christia (MIT)

- Conducted the analysis of the paper: "Can Media Campaigns Empower Women Facing Gender-Based Violence amid COVID-19?" for Fotini Christia, Elizabeth Parker-Magyar (MIT), and Horacio Larreguy.
- Conducted the analysis of the paper: "Accountability under Polarization" for Jose Ramon Enriquez (Harvard), Horacio Larreguy, John Marshall (Columbia), and Alberto Simpser (ITAM).
- Co-author in "Can We Shield Citizens Against Misinformation Through Digital Literacy Training and Fact-checks?" with Antonella Bandiera (ITAM), John Marshall, and Horacio Larreguy.
- Analyzed survey responses for three projects including covariate balance analysis, average treatment effects, heterogeneous effects, reweighted sample to mimic national population, inverse covariance indexes, z-scores, and more.
- Implemented text-analysis techniques.
- Implemented cross-validation and LASSO models.
- Implemented Matching algorithms and constructed Lee Bounds.
- Implemented Inverse propensity score weighting.
- Implemented Multilevel Regression and Post-stratification.

Graduate/Undergraduate Teacher Assistant (ITAM)

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Professor: Horacio Larreguy (ITAM)

Courses: Applied Research I (Masters of Applied Economics) and Economic Research Seminar (Economics department)

• I created tutorials for R, Stata, and LATEX.

- Taught experimental methods such as generalized Difference-in-difference, Instrumental Variables, and Regression Discontinuity.
- Supervised the research project of all students.
- Held office hours to answer specific questions about implementing quasi-experimental methods in R and Stata, as well as exporting the results to LATEX in a presentable manner.

Graduate Teacher Assistant (ITAM)

Jan 2021 - May 2021

Professor: Carlos Urrutia (ITAM)

Course: Dynamic Macroeconomics I (Master of Economic Theory)

- Taught laboratories in MATLAB to put class theory into practice: how to solve the Recursive Neoclassical Growth Model, DSGE models, and Bellman equations including models with heterogeneous agents.
- Graded students' performance in the laboratories and in their final project.

Research Assistant (CIE-ITAM)

June 2020 - Dec 2020

Supervisor: Ignacio Lobato (ITAM)

- Assisted the professor in implementing his paper on non-invertible and non-causal ARMA models in MATLAB.
- Assisted in grading the undergraduate course of Applied Macroeconometrics.

Research Assistant (CIDE-INEGI-ITAM)

June 2019 - Feb 2020

Supervisor: Victor Guerrero (ITAM)

- As a result of our work, INEGI formalized the creation of a business cycle dating committee for the Mexican economy in February 2021.
- Wrote a technical chapter on business cycle methodology.
- Participated in the first international congress of business cycle dating committees from around the world.
- Prepared presentations for fortnightly meetings.

Tutorship Program (ITAM)

Jan 2019 - June 2020

Member of the minor faculty of Statistics and Mathematics.

- Answered questions and gave advice on statistics and mathematics to any student at ITAM.
- Supervised departmental examinations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Licenses and certifications	
Data Science: R Basics by HarvardX (certificate)	June 2019
Data Science: Machine Learning by HarvardX (certificate)	July 2022
High-Dimensional Data Analysis by HarvardX (certificate)	July 2022
Using Python for Research by HarvardX (certificate)	$\mathrm{Aug}\ 2022$
Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp (certificate)	$\mathrm{Aug}\ 2022$
Neural Networks and Deep Learning by DeepLearning.AI (certificate)	Sept 2022
Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning,	
Regularization and Optimization by DeepLearning.AI (certificate)	Sept 2022
Programming level	
R / RStudio	• • • •
MATLAB	• • • •
Python	
Stata	
Java	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
EViews	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
C#	
Honors and awards	

- Research Award: Honorable mention in Applied Mathematics (July 2022).
- Research Award: Honorable mention in Economics (Jun 2022).
- Sage Fellowship, Cornell University Rejected (Mar 2022).

- Undergraduate Student Scholarships at ITAM (Aug 2015 Aug 2018).
- Finalist at MIT Delta V Epic lab (2017).
- Business School Excellence Award ITAM (Aug 2015 Dec 2016).
- High School Valedictorian Instituto Chapultepec (2015).

Publications

- Bandiera Antonella, Horacio L. John M. Daniela P. and Manuel Q. 2022. "Can We Shield Citizens Against Misinformation Through Digital Literacy Training and Fact-checks?" Working paper.
- Christia Fotini, Horacio L., Eizabeth P., and Manuel Q. 2022. "Can Media Campaigns Empower Women Facing Gender-Based Violence amid COVID-19?" Working paper.
- Associate Researcher: Antón A. et al. 2020. "Propuesta para crear un comité de fechado de los ciclos económicos en México". INEGI. México. URL: http://internet.contenidos.inegi.org.mx/contenidos/productos/prod_serv/contenidos/espanol/bvinegi/productos/nueva_estruc/promo/GTDCFC_2020.pdf.